Guide to the Class banners ARCH091
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
Class banners
1998-2015
Class of 2002 - Class of 2019
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
ARCH091
18 Pieces
The collection contains the University of Hartford class banners for the Class of 2002 to the Class of 2019.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to all researchers.
Historical Note
According to Lee Peters, The banner tradition was started in 1999 by Walter Harrison during his second year as president. Each year new first year students sign a large banner during their orientation. The banner is then hung up during convocation. After convocation, the president and the students walk over the bridge to the area in from of the library for a barbeque.
This activity should not be confused with the "crossing the bridge" that takes place during orientation when students first meet with a faculty advisor. This "crossing the bridge" is metaphorical and symbolizes the transition from high school to college.
The banner hangs briefly in the 1877 room. The banner is then hung in the library entrance for four years. The banner is taken down and hung at the class' commencement ceremony. Afterwards, the banner is sent to the University Archives.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of banners signed by each class at the University of Hartford, starting with the Class of 2002 through the Class of 2019.
Arrangement
The banners are arranged in chronological order.
Cultural artifacts; banners; Commencement ceremonies; Academic rites and ceremonies; University of Hartford -- Students; Harrison, Walter Lee; University of Hartford
- Class of 2002, 1998 (Object 0207303183025)
- Class of 2003, 1999 (Object 0207303183033)
- Class of 2004, 2000 (Object 0207303183108)
- Class of 2005, 2001 (Object 0207303175542)
- Class of 2006, 2002 (Object 0207303183116)
- Class of 2007, 2003 (Object 0207303183140)
- Class of 2008, 2004 (Object 0207303183074)
- Class of 2009, 2005 (Object 0207303183157)
- Class of 2010, 2006 (Object 0207303183124)
- Class of 2011, 2007 (Object 0207303183082)
- Class of 2012, 2008 (Object 0207303183066)
- Class of 2013, 2009 (Object 0207303183041)
  General
  This banner appears to have a cigarette burn.
- Class of 2014, 2010 (Object 0207303183090)
- Class of 2015, 2011 (Object 0207303183132)
- Class of 2016, 2012 (Object 0096207303175)
- Class of 2017, 2013 (Object 0207303175088)
- Class of 2018, 2014 (Object 0207303183058)
  Biographical / Historical
  This banner was signed by the class of 2018 in 2014. It then was hung in the library on the north wall above the stairs for the next four years. In the past, the banners rotated around the main entrance of the library, but this did not happen between 2014 and 2018. As a result, the class banner was in direct sunlight for four years and the signatures became severely faded. To remedy this, the class of 2018 resigned their class banner on the day of the 2018 undergraduate commencement ceremony.
  Scope and Contents
  This is the class of 2018 banner, which was signed originally in 2014 and resigned on May 20, 2018.
- Class of 2019, 2015 (Object 0207303181532)